it's not any secret that a barbell is
one of the most versatile pieces of
equipment you could add to your home gym
and livingfit just dropped some heat now
y'all I literally just unboxed these a
few minutes ago now I've obviously done
my due diligence and done my research
there's a lot to like about these
barbells on paper but in this video
today we're really going to put them to
the test and see what they're made of so
kick back and relax and hang out for a
little bit as I break down both of these
barbells
correct
[Music]
yo what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I've got two count them two
barbells from living fit that I'm gonna
be breaking down for y'all in this video
today I'm gonna tell you everything you
need to know about these barbells from
the price and the features the pros and
the cons but you know most importantly
who should or maybe should not add these
to their home gym now before I get going
you know start talking my head off and
into the camera I gotta let you guys
know we've reviewed a ton of barbells on
barbin.com so if you want to browse our
best list just go and search barvin best
barbells that article is going to pull
up for you and you can find out for
yourself which ones that we like the
best
okay
[Music]
all right so let's talk about what I
like about these barbells and once again
these are my initial thoughts because
I'm really just now putting my hands on
these the knurling is really nice you
know it's nice and moderate these are
multi-purpose bars which is you know why
it's moderate it's not going to tear up
your hands as you go to do you know a
power clean or any other Olympic style
lift and speaking of that you know once
again these are multi-purpose bars and
that's because of the pairing of
bushings and bearings in the loading
sleeves it's going to provide a pretty
solid rate of spin really going to allow
you to you know twist that barbell and
get under it for those power cleans for
example I really like how there's two
different coating options right here so
you have Chrome and cerakote this is
really nice you know the cerakote's
going to be your best bet if you're
keeping all your gear in a non-climate
controlled room you don't have AC you
know that humidity can really cause the
barbell to you know get some Rust and
corrosion on it and you know next to
stainless steel stair coat is the best
option you could ask for both of these
barbells can also load up to 1500 pounds
which is a really nice number and then
either way whichever one you go for
you're not going to be spending more
than 225 bucks so this is a really nice
budget friendly option
[Music]
okay so I want to take a second and just
talk about a few potential cons you may
run into and first of all we got to talk
about the packaging so barbell packaging
isn't necessarily the best by any means
in general but when I got both of these
barbells the plastic end caps that are
on that cardboard packaging were just
gone they're missing nowhere to be found
now barbells weren't hanging out you
know there's no visible damage or
anything like that just keep that in
mind because if it happened to me it
might happen to you too all right now I
want to transition to talking about
tensile strength and if you don't know
what tensile strength is just really
quick it's essentially going to tell you
how strong a barbell is all right so
this ranges from 150 000 PSI to 230 some
of them around 235 000 PSI so it's
basically just going to tell you you
know how much force how much weight
everything that a barbell can handle
before it starts to bend or you know
maybe even fracture that's gonna be
really hard to do but you know still
that that's it's nice knowing what that
number is all right so these barbells
it's kind of confusing on the living fit
website it says they range from 100 180
to 210 000 PSI I've honestly never
really seen that before you know most
companies just have it you know written
out clear as day you know what it is now
let's say they are 180 000 PSI that's
still plenty for you know most weight
lifters only time you know you're really
gonna have to worry about that my
opinion is if you're you know power
cleaning some absurd weight okay so it
should be fine for most people it would
just be nice if it was you know
perfectly laid out and disclosed as I
just mentioned also this chrome honestly
it looks sweet it looks awesome you know
brand new out of that packaging looks
amazing but you know if you're not in a
non-climate controlled room this is not
going to be the best bet for you it's
gonna you know protect against rust and
corrosion better than bare steel will
but like
still you're gonna have to clean it more
so than you would with this cerakote bar
so definitely just keep that in mind and
then you know really this isn't that big
of a deal but these aren't going to be
the best at any one lift and that's
because they're multi-purpose bars
they're going to allow you to do
everything but you know if you're a
dedicated power lifter or you know an
Olympic lifter you're definitely going
to want to go for a specialty bar
foreign
[Music]
okay so let's transition into talking
about some money now and once again you
know both of these barbells are a really
nice budget-friendly option okay so this
chrome one is going to run you right
around 200 bucks while the cerakote is
about 225. now we compare this to the
rest of the market
it's like really really solid price
point for both of them I mean yeah you
could find a cheaper one than this than
this chrome one right here but it's
gonna be cheaper for a reason that's
because the quality is just not gonna be
there now these both feel really nice in
my hands we're going to really test them
out in a second and you know put them to
the test like I said and do some power
cleans and stuff with it in a minute but
you know first you know reactions these
seem you know really high quality and
this cerakote bar in particular is a
really nice deal in my opinion you know
most companies are charging about 100
bucks more for their cerakote bar so you
know what you're getting out of both of
these I think it's a really nice deal
[Music]
okay so let's take a second and talk
about the build and some of the features
with both of these barbells so remember
you have your choice of coding with
chrome and cerakote but either way
they're both made of alloy steel
86.6 inches in length 16 inch loading
sleeves and they have a diameter of 28
millimeters now it's worth mentioning
that both of these bars are only
available in 20 kilograms so if you're
looking for 10 or 15 you're just gonna
have to keep looking elsewhere both
These Bars can handle up to 1500 pounds
of weight and that tensile strength is
in a range of 180 to 210 000 PSI if I
can figure that out you know later on
I'll definitely you know make an update
but as of right now that's that's all I
got for you there now the knurling is
pretty solid and that's actually a
really good thing obviously you know you
get a good grip but you know a lot of
times compared to stainless steel
bars with a coating don't have as good
of a you know grippy feel I guess you
could say and honestly I feel pretty
impressed by both of these right off the
bat now it might that might change once
I you know start working out with them
here in a second but
honestly this feels pretty good and I
can't even tell a difference between
either one of these so it's not like one
necessarily gives you a better grip than
the other so that's really nice now you
do have dual neural markings right here
so the ones on the inside are you know
the standard of the international
powerlifting Federation while the ones
on the outside or by the international
weightlifting Federation so this is
really nice you know these are here
because they are in fact multi-purpose
bars now you don't have a center
knurling right here
you know personally for me that's
totally fine
a lot of times most of the time actually
with the multi-purpose bar you're not
going to have that but you know if you
have more of an emphasis and power
lifting you might want a little bit of
knurling right here it's not it's not
going to be as abrasive as you know out
here but that definitely helps a little
bit you know when putting the bar on
your upper back for your squats and
actually having a little bit of a knurl
right there is sometimes pretty good
when you know getting a power clean you
know it lets it helps it stick to your
chest a little bit the sleeves do have a
bit of a grooved pattern they're not cut
super deep or anything but those are
designed to help keep your weight plates
in their original placement so they
don't slide down you know the sleeves as
you're dropping that bar repeatedly I
would still toss on some weight collars
you know you can never be too safe and
speaking of the sleeves they have a
pretty solid rate of Spin and that's
because there's ball bearings and Brass
bushings within them and that's just you
know providing that spin now they don't
you know spin out of control or anything
which is nice for your power lifts but
you know since they don't miss
necessarily spin as fast as a bar that
only has bearings it might not you know
feel the exact same way when you're
going to do those power cleans now you
can definitely get it done still I'm not
you know knocking it by any means just
definitely keep that in mind
[Music]
thank you
all right guys so I just want to show
y'all up close you know all the
fine-tuned details of these barbells and
we're going to demonstrate everything in
just a second so obviously you know you
have Chrome right here cerakote nice for
different reasons you know
we have AC in here so this chrome will
work nice in here but if we didn't we'd
be going after the cerakote for sure
just because it has a little bit more
protection from rust and corrosion now
obviously you don't have a center knurl
right here even if you did it wouldn't
be very abrasive but that can come in
handy with you know different lifts such
as a power clean keep it on your chest
and definitely you know for your
squatting just keeping it on your upper
back right there let's move a little
further down the line knurling right
here it's really nice it's not too
passive it's definitely not abrasive
which is a really good thing with a
multi-purpose bar and once again I
cannot tell a difference between you
know the grip right here from the Chrome
and the cerakote that's really nice you
know a lot of times you can kind of tell
that's not the case here so that's good
now you have your dual neural markings
right here ipf on the inside iwf on the
outside industry standard which is
really cool right there as well now you
can see I'm a little bit better on the
Chrome one than this cerakote but you
have your brass bushings right here and
then you have your bearings on the
inside you obviously can't see them now
this is what is going to provide a
pretty solid rate of spin now they don't
spin as you know freely and as fast as a
bar that only has bearings but honestly
this is pretty solid for you know what
you're getting especially with the price
point that's this is really nice now
both of them do have a little bit of a
Groove pattern right here on the sleeves
not that deep you almost can't tell if
you're on your fingers over it but
that's designed to help keep those
plates locked into place over time you
definitely don't want them moving down
down the sleeve right here and it's
really nice definitely get some you know
weight collars still but
it's gonna help you out a little bit and
one more thing you know these are 16
inch loading sleeves you can be able to
put a pretty decent amount of weight on
that's also you know industry standard
as well
um these can handle up to 1500 pounds so
pretty much everybody or I guess it's
say everybody can get some solid usage
out of these and then that tinsel
strength remember it's 180 210 000 PSI
not really sure you know which end of
the spectrum it really is but either way
it's going to be solid for most you know
at home weight lifters now I'm gonna
move you know the Craftsman out of the
way we're gonna throw some weight on
here and really put these to the test so
let's get to it all right so I wanted to
go ahead and show you guys just you know
how versatile These Bars really are and
I wanted to have everything set up
properly beforehand but this is the
first time I put weight on this bar
right here and as you can see you know
there's already you know some blemishes
I guess you want to call them now I
don't know if that's because of the
plate or if it's necessarily because of
the bar maybe it's you know a mix of two
it's not going to negative impact you
know the life of the bar but it's just
not going to look as pretty so that's
definitely something that I wanted to
mention and to show you guys up close
because once again it's the first time I
put a weight plate on this barbell so
anyways we go ahead and lock this guy in
and I want to see if it does it on the
other end too I think it will but let's
just go ahead and find out
yeah see you got those squiggly lines
going right down the sleeve right there
that's just not ideal that's that's less
than ideal right there but you know it's
okay at the end of the day so anyways
let's go ahead and do do a Power Clean
here and just kind of see how it feels
in my hands
honestly that felt pretty good
um pretty impressed by the the spin
right here so the sleeves spin with no
weight is on it but you know once you
have weight on it and you're sitting
here on the ground that bar is actually
what's spinning so honestly
that was pretty impressive definitely
gets the job done so let me catch my
breath let's go ahead and bench press
real quick
all right so while you know not as much
going on right there as a you know
opposed to a power clean and what you
can really feel that grip felt really
good in my hands you know got a little
bit of some knurling markings on my hand
right there
honestly it's pretty grippy not too
abrasive and that's what makes these
barbells so versatile
[Music]
all right so let's talk about who should
snag this barbell from living fit for
their home gym we got to talk about
money first you know if you're working
with a tight budget or maybe you just
don't want to spend you know up to 500
on one barbell
both of these and either one of these
it's going to be a really solid option
you're not going to spend more than 225
bucks that's going to create more wiggle
room for you to add more gear to your
gym you know whether that be a
kettlebell adjustable dumbbells maybe a
weight bench maybe even a relatively
cheap squat rack either way it's going
to free up a little bit of money so
that's really nice also you know the
different coding options is really nice
too you know if you're having your gear
in a garage or anywhere that's not
climate controlled and it gets really
hot and humid the cerakote's going to be
you know really solid for you they're
also you know since they are
multi-purpose bars you're gonna be able
to do all of your lifts you know as I
said earlier might not necessarily be
the best any one thing but you know
having that versatility is a really nice
touch and then lastly is the tensile
strings yeah I know it's a little bit
unknown since it's you know from 180 to
210 000 PSI but even if it is at 180 000
PSI you know that's going to be plenty
for most weightlifters
[Music]
now believe it or not there are a few
instances where somebody might not want
to purchase these barbells so let's talk
about that now if you're a dedicated
power lifter or an Olympic lifter you're
going to want to go after a specialty
bar rather than a multi-purpose bar like
this right here got to talk about the
Chrome
it looks great you know it's gonna hold
up pretty nice but if you know you're
not going to be you know on top of
cleaning it from time to time but you
should do that anyways if you're not
going to be on top of cleaning it from
time to time and it is you know in a hot
humid room it's gonna you know get some
Rust and corrosion on it so definitely
keep that in mind and then lastly you
know if you're looking for a junior size
bar or a Bello bar you're just simply
it's not going to get that here
first
all right that's all I have for you guys
today on the living fit barbell I
personally think these are a really
solid purchase you know they do have
that budget friendly price tag which is
really nice they're about as
multi-purpose as it gets because of the
bearings and bushings and the loading
sleeves and especially you know with
this moderate knurling it's going to
allow you to do all of your lifts just
remember you know they're not going to
be necessarily the best at any one thing
thanks for hanging out with me y'all I
hope this video was really helpful and I
was able to break down everything you
need to know about this barbell as
always keep your eyes peeled for my next
video but for now you should absolutely
head over to barbin.com we have a full
written review about this bar just ready
for you to read all you got to do is
search bar Bend livingfit barbell review
it's going to pull right up you can go
over every single thing we talked about
here today I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]
excellent